

heuristic evaluation cognitive walkthrough time and method engineering

EXPERTISE

Turnkey business solutions systems analysis change management communication methodologies

SKILLS

data visualization
workflow optimization
presentation
communication design
statistical analysis
sdlc methods
office suite

TOOLS

B III

excel SQL/mySQL

COMPLIANCE

ANSI OSHA ISO DOT

PROJECTS

six sigma black belt java pedagogy methods

COMMUNITY

inter/national disaster relief habitat for humanity small group leadership logistics management (NPO/NGOs)

INTERESTS

neon art bending whitewater kayaking large scale gourmet cooking

ANALYSIS

I use a multitude of tools and experiences that bring a comprehensive approach to evaluate systems, processes, objects, and personnel. I achieve this through a mix of initial communication with stakeholders and departments, and use this information to develop the framework for developing scope and planning resources to exceed <client/project> expectations.

COMMUNICATION

I ensure that our team develops time-sensitive seminars, conferences, and meetings designed to explicate the scope and complexities of deadlines in a unified environment for clients and team members. I develop daily business interactions to maintain a positive milieu, within a prescribed common creative atmosphere, vital to the team's success in daily challenges, ultimately to the project, company, and client.

BUDGETING

Listening to the needs of the project's stakeholders, I tailor a solution using a top down method for providing the needs of budget conscious clients, or a ground up design for customized turnkey solutions. These hybrid approaches are weighted towards the common voice of the client, where detail oriented solutions are applied along the common tones throughout the client's organization.

TEAMWORK

Limiting task oriented teams to no more than 7 persons, with a wide assortment of experience and a solid rubric for life cycle development of projects enables synergistic teamwork practices and enables succinct solutions with minimal interruptions. When a group is given full control with the understanding of full accountability, time and time again the group as a whole is able to provide the necessary decisions to achieve positive progression.

INTELLIGENCE

With diverse hobbies, experiences, contacts, and interests, I bring a special perspective to providing successful solutions, on time, and above and beyond requirements. I owe my successes to borrowed approaches in scouting, mentorship, and previous successes where developing a strong approach to looking through a problem to see its solution has allowed me to approach situations with objective clarity.

ENTHUSIASM

Understanding the importance of the products and services needed of the end users and clients, and forming an environment, which highlights those needs, allows me to convey a quick, calm, succinct product. There is nothing more successful than a team with a common goal and the will to accomplish that goal as their own.

TIME

I operate on a business healthy approach of meeting the requirements of the project; both personnel/clients' and planning/execution are balanced to achieve an overall positive relationship with the client, team members, and other staff in a warm and inviting manner.



EDUCATION

University Of North Carolina At Charlotte

B.A. in Communication Studies: Mass Media focused in Women's Studies (Gendered Communication) - December 2007

Central Piedmont Community College

Currently Enrolled in Black Belt Six Sigma Certification - 2011

AWARDS & HONORS

Platinum Quality Recipient - Developed equipment inventory resulting in asset recovery in excess of \$30K across Region - 2008 National South Eastern Women's Studies Association-SEWSA speaker on self-researched topic: Gendered Communication - 2008 Most Improved Service Manager - 2007

Eagle Scout - Earned 2003 and proud to still be currently

EXPERIENCE

FedEx Ground MAR 2006 -

Ground Contractor Corporate Liason- IT Development Projects JUL 2010 -

- •J2EE development analyzing business models to highlight revenue oppurtunity (mySQL, JSF/myFaces, Spring, Hibernate, Tomcat, Maven, XML, and X/HTML, with Git versioning) in a traditional Waterfall devloping environment comprised solely of myself, end to end in Eclipse
- •Customized data reportingand data entry of PDF, email (SMTP), XML, and CVS into single comprehensive queryable presentations (Sikuli)
- •Basic data verification and session/transaction steps within program to cleanse and prevent rogue data from entering database
- •Database design with Business level logic for security management of CRUD user and data history retention
- •Chose J2EE and associated technologies and self taught to account for 50 requirements including scaling and future support of program
- •Self started business oppurtunity for business analytics for incumbent raw data for shared success roles by contractors and corporation Southern Regional Vision Implementation Manager FEB 2010 DEC 2011
- Engineer new frameworks implementations for all stakeholders to reduce release increments during release (Agile methodology)
- Project Manager for 20 terminals with a proprietary sorting technology, while exceeding process standards, despite increasing staffing, and reducing task oriented processes, effecting 12% of daily package volume in the company, all on or ahead of a 10 month schedule
- •Identify an SQL security hole in an outsourced employee HR website, affecting +40% of FedEx Operations, saving +30M in liability Southern Divisional Preload Quality Initiative Manager 3 FEB 2009 JAN 2010
- •Develop new sortation devices to augment package handler training and sortation using open source software and data implemented within Excel (VBA) eliminating licensing/rollout limitations, with full network release under 3 months costing \$40/terminal (500+ terminals)
- •SCADA process improvements using to reduce workflow of hourly workers by 50%, totaling a 5% increase across all productivity Dock Service Manager 3 JAN 2007 JAN 2009
- •Develop apps for time sensitive workflows enabling real time visual presentation of current/potential issues (as400, Excel, XP mobile)

P/T Service Manager JUL 2006 - DEC 2006

P/T Package Handler MAR 2006 - JUN 2006

•Rearrange loading techniques with a safer scalable visual solution for loading contractor vehicles for daily loads (as400, Excel)

Harris Teeter

JUN 2003 - MAR 2006

Grocery Manager

- •QA automatic inventory control system for business use (incomplete order shipment, shrink, peak, sales) using visual trend data analysis
- •Manage three adjacent stores and retrain employees on the proper procedures, methodologies, and system processes Customer Service Clerk
- Assist a team of 10+ associates on the front line while ensuring the customers' needs/wants are met and exceeded

ACTIVITIES

- •Local, State, National, and International relief efforts (Habitat for Humanity, Cherokee, Blackfeet, Katrina/Gulf Coast, Haiti, Bahamas) Ongoing
- President of United Christian Fellowship to organize, develop, and lead varying sizes of volunteers 2005 2008
- •Liaison for NPOs: Habitat for Humanity International-logistics, Cooperative Campus Ministry-management 2005 Ongoing
- •Logistics for NGO: Hearts with Haiti 2008 Ongoing, Logistics Board of Director Habitat for Humanity International 2009 Ongoing

SKILLS

- Proficient in Windows, Linux, UNIX, OSX, HTML, Excel (w/VBA scripting), Access, PowerPoint, Ariba, Python, SQL
- •Skilled in Data merging/migration, change-management, implementation, and planning large scale cost saving efforts
- Established knowledge of regulatory compliance, assessment, and preparedness of NERC, CIP, ANSI, ISO, OSHA, Web 2.0
- Public Speaking/Presenting/MC, Supervision, Team Building, and Leadership
- •Systems and Structure Analysis/Devlopement, Liaison for programmers and stakeholders, Construct data visuals to expedite business roles

CERTIFICATIONS

•SCADA / NERC / CIP / OSHA / ANSI / ISO / DOT - 2009 •First Aid / CPR certified - 2010 (valid until 2013) •Operations / Leadership - 2008



